Finding Aid for the Edwin Bower Hesser Papers LSC.1071
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Assorted paper materials, 1917-1958; 6.5 boxes, 4.5 oversize boxes
  - B. Periodicals, 1920-1958
    - Sunbathing and Health Magazine, 1946 September; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 21)
      Vol. 8, No. 5; magazine devoted to nudist activities. Comprised of photographs of nude men, women, and children.
    - Today's Health, 1955 February; 1 item. (Box 21, Folder 22)
      Vol. 33, No. 2; cover photo by Hesser.
    - True Confessions (1 of 2), 1947 January, April; 6 items. (Box 21, Folder 23)
      Vol. 48, No. 294, Vol. 49, and No. 297; cover photos by Hesser.
    - True Confessions (2 of 2), 1947, 1953; 5 items. (Box 21, Folder 24)
      Vol. 49, No. 300 and Vol. 60, No. 366; cover photos by Hesser.
    - True Romance, 1947 May-June; 3 items. (Box 21, Folder 25)
      Vol. 45, No. 3 and No. 4; cover photos by Hesser. Cover and title page only May issue (No. 3).
    - Unidentified publications (1 of 2), ca. 1926-1945; 18 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Assorted and unidentified magazine advertisements, article photos, and cover photos. Includes shot of Greta Garbo (for oversize materials see box 39, folder 13).
    - U.S. Camera (1 of 2), 1948-1950; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Covers from Vol. 13, No. 12; also includes December and August covers from unknown volume and number. Cover photos by Hesser (for oversize materials see box 29, folder 14).
    - Scrapbook (3 of 3), ca. 1920-1930; 1 item. (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Compiled oversize scrapbook of magazine shots by Hesser. Includes photos from Pictureplay, Photoplay, Motion Picture, and Screenland of numerous silent film actresses and models.
    - Arts Monthly Pictorial (3 of 3), 1922 May; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Oversized first issue, Vol. 1, No.1; Hesser is credited as founder, editor, and photographer. Cover photo is of Gloria Swanson.
    - Capper's Farmer, 1947 September; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 2)
      Oversize cover from September issue.
    - The Florida Times-Union Parade Magazine, 1946 April 7; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 3)
      Oversize cover from Vol. 5, No. 40.
    - Hit! Annual, 1949; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Oversize cover from Spring 1949 issue; cover by Eve Hesser.
    - Hollywood Magazine (2 of 2), 1931 March, May; 3 items. (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Oversize mounted covers; cover photos by Hesser. Subjects of covers include: Marguerite Churchill, Leila Hymas, and Carole Lombard. July cover from unknown year and volume.
    - Ladies' Home Journal, 1927, 1950-1951; 6 items. (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Oversize issues; covers by Hesser. Includes two lithographs of covers from August 1950 and 1951. Also includes single page from January 1927 issue and advertisement for August 1951 issue.
    - Los Angeles Times- This Week Magazine, 1947 July 20 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Oversize issue; cover by Hesser.
    - Movie Classic, 1935 July (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Oversize cover proofs from July 1935 issue; cover by Hesser. Shot of Alice Faye.
    - Picture-Wise, 1946 August; 2 items. (Box 39, Folder 9)
      Oversize issue, Vol. 1, No. 7; cover by Hesser.
    - Startling Detective Adventures, ca. 1940 April; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 10)
      Oversize mounted April cover; cover photo by Hesser. Cover is from unknown year and volume.
    - Studio Art Studies (2 of 2), ca. 1930; 1 item. (Box 39, Folder 11)
      Oversize mounted cover from unknown year, month, and volume.
    - Tatler, 1923 August-September; 6 items. (Box 39, Folder 12)
      Oversize pages from No. 1153, 1159, 1160, and 1161 issues; photos by Hesser. Subjects include: Germaine Mitty, Mae Murray, Vanda Hoff, Theda Bara, and Aubrey Hastings with family.
    - Unidentified publications (2 of 2), ca. 1926-1945; 9 items. (Box 39, Folder 13)
      Oversized, assorted ,and unidentified magazine covers, photos, and pinups.
    - U.S. Camera (2 of 2), 1946-1947; 4 items. (Box 39, Folder 14)
      Oversize covers and title pages from Vol. 9 No. 5, and December issue from unknown volume and number. Cover photos by Eve Hesser.
    - Scrapbook (1 of 3), ca. 1930-1940; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Compiled oversize scrapbook of magazine covers and lithographs of photos by Hesser. Includes many Hollywood Magazine covers.
    - Scrapbook (2 of 3), ca. 1930-1940; 1 item. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Compiled oversize scrapbook of magazine covers by Hesser.
  - C. Posing ideas, ca. 1925-1958
    This subseries consists of assorted clippings, lithographs, illustrations, and magazine covers used for researching posing ideas for photo shoots. Includes lithographs by Adolf Armstrong, bound workbooks, and previously foldered materials organized by subject. Files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Workbook (1 of 2), 1934-1958; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Bound workbook containing ideas for photo shoots and notes on photo equipment. Contains numerous pages that are not bound and have been added to workbook.
    - Workbook (2 of 2), ca. 1946-1952; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Bound workbook containing ideas for photo shoots and notes on photo equipment.
    - Assorted women, ca. 1925-1930; 19 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Lithographs of various pastel illustrations of women modeling and printed photographs. Majority of illustrations by Adolf Armstrong (for oversize materials see box 33, folder 2).
    - College Humor magazine covers, ca.1926-1931; 23 items. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Illustrations depicting modeling women. All illustrations by Adolf Armstrong.
    - Screenland magazine covers, ca. 1924-1930; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Illustrations depicting modeling starlets; includes Gloria Swanson, Greta Garbo, and Evelyn Brent. All illustrations by Adolf Armstrong.
    - Oversize assorted folders, ca, 1930-1940; 19 items. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Large manila original envelopes labeled by subject; contain clippings, magazine covers, drawings, and lithographs of posing ideas. Includes loose materials.
    - Oversize assorted women, ca. 1925-1930; 17 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Lithographs of various pastel illustrations of women modeling. Many illustrations by Adolf Armstrong.
    - Oversize miscellaneous, ca. 1925-1935; 11 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Magazine covers, calendars, clippings, and sketches of landscapes, poses, and various scenarios used for posing/photo ideas.
- Color transparencies, ca. 1936-1945; 1.5 boxes
  This series consists of 4 x 5" and 5 x 7" Kodachrome and other color stock transparencies shot by Edwin Bower Hesser. Unmounted transparencies were placed in envelopes during processing, while formerly mounted transparencies remain in their original state. Files are arranged alphabetically according to subject.
  - Animals, ca. 1936-1945; 14 items. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    4 x 5" color shots of various animals such as dogs, horses, and donkeys. Includes 4 mounted transparencies of animals with Dorothy Roberts and Barbara Lawrence.
  - Children, ca. 1936-1945; 17 items. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    4 x 5" color shots of unidentified young boys and girls.
  - Couples, ca. 1936-1945; 14 items. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    4 x 5" color shots of various couples. Includes 4 mounted transparencies of Jo Ann Smith and Dorothy Roberts.
  - Men outside, ca. 1936-1945; 2 items. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    4 x 5" color shots of men outside in nature scenes.
  - Outdoor scenes, ca. 1936-1945; 5 items. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    4 x 5" color shots of various outdoor scenes.
  - Still life, ca. 1936-1945; 3 items. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    4 x 5" mounted color shots of flowers and hanging fox furs on a wall.
  - Women--casual attire, ca. 1936-1945; 25 items. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    4 x 5" color shots of women in casual attire, such as sweaters, blouses, and dresses. Includes 4 mounted transparencies of Dorothy Roberts and Colleen Townsend.
  - Women--close-ups, ca. 1936-1945; 5 items. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    4 x 5" color close-up portraits of women in various poses.
  - Women--exterior modeling, ca. 1936-1945; 28 items. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    4 x 5" color shots of women modeling outdoors. Framed in medium and long shots. Includes 5 mounted transparencies of Peggy MacLean, Toby Macklin, Jo Ann Smith, and Anne Stuart.
  - Women--festive, international, ruffled, and costume attire modeling, ca. 1936-1945; 8 items. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    4 x 5" and 5 x 7" color shots of women modeling ruffled, low cut, and strapless attire. Includes shots of women in Latin-inspired dress and women in various costumes. Includes 2 mounted transparencies of Barbara Lawrence and Jo Anne Smith.
  - Women--formal attire, ca. 1936-1945; 7 items. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    4 x 5" color shots of women in formal attire, such as furs and gowns. Includes 3 mounted transparencies of Jo Ann Smith.
  - Women--hats, veils, and headwear modeling, ca. 1936-1945; 25 items. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    4 x 5" and 5 x 7" color shots of women modeling hats, veils, or other types of headwear. Includes 14 mounted transparencies of Marilyn Buford, Jo Ann Smith, Colleen Townsend, and Madeleine Martin.
  - Women--props modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1936-1945; 33 items. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    4 x 5" color shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, pottery, brushes, and fabric. Includes 6 mounted transparencies of Ferne Rice and Madeleine Martin.
  - Women--props modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1936-1945; 8 items. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    4 x 5" color shots of women modeling with various props. Includes shots of women modeling with flowers, fruit, pottery, brushes, and fabric. Includes 8 mounted transparencies of Barbara Lawrence, Betty Alvord, Madelyn Martin, Marie Denham, Toby Macklin.
  - Women--semi-formal and business attire, ca. 1936-1945; 15 items. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    4 x 5" color shots of women in semi-formal and business attire, such as blouses, dresses, and suits. Includes 5 mounted transparencies of Marie Denham and Dorothy Roberts.
  - Women--summer ware, ca. 1936-1945; 11 item. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    4 x 5" color shots of women in bathing suites and beach or pool attire. Includes 3 mounted transparencies of Betty Alvord, Toby Macklin, and Viki Vance.
  - Women--winter and Christmas attire modeling (1 of 2), ca. 1936-1945; 30 items. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    4 x 5" color shots of women modeling winter and Christmas themed attire, such as ski suits, skis, hooded coats, etc. Includes 6 mounted transparencies of Marie Denham and Madeline Martin.
  - Women--winter and Christmas attire modeling (2 of 2), ca. 1936-1945; 6 items. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    4 x 5" mounted color shots of women modeling winter and Christmas themed attire, such as ski suits, skis, hooded coats, etc. Includes 6 mounted transparencies of Peggy MacLean, Kerry Vaughan, Anne Stuart, Adelle Lincoln, and Ferne Rice.
- Hollywood personalities, ca. 1920-1938; 0.5 boxes, 2 oversize boxes
  This series consists of black and white prints, Hessercolor prints, and transparencies of Hollywood personalities and Technicolor film stills shot by Edwin Bower Hesser. A select number of oversize prints were mounted for preservation purposes. Files are arranged alphabetically according to surname of featured subject(s).
  - Astor, Mary, 1931 February 25; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits.
  - Becky Sharp--production stills, 1935; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    8 x 10" Hessercolor prints of stills from the motion picture Becky Sharp.
  - Bennett, Constance, ca. 1920-1938; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    5 x 7" black and white portraits.
  - Blondell, Joan, 1931 April 7; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits. Black and white color values from Hessercolor photograph.
  - Brian, Mary, ca. 1920-1938; 18 items. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    6.5 x 8.5" and 4.5 x 6.5" black and white portraits. Black and white color values from Hessercolor photograph.
  - Brown, John Mack, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    4.5 x 6.5" black and white portraits.
  - Carlisle, Mary, 1931; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Carroll, Nancy, 1931 February 11; 7 items. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits. 6.5 x 8.5" black and white nitrate Hessercolor negatives in Box 55 stored at nitrate vaults in Hollywood.
  - Colbert, Claudette, ca. 1932-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor transparency and print.
  - Crawford, Joan, ca. 1932-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor transparencies.
  - Cummings, Constance, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Del Rio, Dolores, ca. 1932-1938; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor transparency and black and white portraits of black and white color values from Hessercolor.
  - Dell, Claudia, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 18)
    6.5 x 8.5" and 4 x 5" black and white portraits.
  - D'Orsay, Fifi, ca. 1932-1938; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Dove, Billie, ca. 1932-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 20)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor transparency and black and white portrait.
  - Evans, Madge, 1931 July 7; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 21)
    8 x 9.5" black and white portrait.
  - Fairbanks, Douglas, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 22)
    8 x 10" black and white portraits (for additional Fairbanks image, see box 22, folder 23).
  - Fairbanks, Douglas and Mary Pickford, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 23)
    8 x 10" black and white portrait (for additional Pickford image, see box 22, folder 23).
  - Gaynor, Janet, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 24)
    4 x 6.5" black and white portraits.
  - Gilbert, John, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 25)
    5 x 7" black and white portrait with Gilbert's signature printed on photograph.
  - Gulliver, Dorothy, 1928; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Harlow, Jean, ca. 1932-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 27)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor transparency.
  - Johnson, Avis, 1931 October 3; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 28)
    5 x 8" black and white portrait.
  - Knapp, Evelyn, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 29)
    6.5 x 8.5" black and white portrait.
  - La Cucaracha--production stills, 1934; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 30)
    8 x 10" Hessercolor prints of stills from the motion picture La Cucaracha.
  - Landi, Elissa, 1931 May 14; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Lee, Lila, ca. 1920-1938; 8 items. (Box 22, Folder 32)
    7 x 5" and 6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits.
  - Love, Bessie, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 33)
    7.5 x 9.5" black and white portrait.
  - Lowell, Joan, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 34)
    5 x 7" black and white portrait.
  - Marsh, Marion, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - McConnell, Gladys, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Morgan, Jeanne, 1928; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 37)
    5 x 8" and 6.5 x 8.5" black and white portraits.
  - Nissen, Greta, 1931 April 8; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - O'Neil, Sally, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 39)
    8 x 10" black and white portrait.
  - O'Sullivan, Maureen, 1931; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Page, Anita, 1931; 9 items. (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Pickford, Mary, ca. 1920-1938; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 42)
    5 x 8" black and white portraits and one fragile and torn photo in mylar (for additional Pickford image, see box 22, folder 23).
  - Sidney, Sylvia [?], ca. 1932-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Stanwick, Barbara, 1931 April 7; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Stuart, Nick, ca. 1920-1938; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Temple, Shirley, ca. 1932-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 46)
    6.5 x 8.5" Hessercolor print. Damaged and torn.
  - Twelvetrees, Helen, ca. 1932-1938; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Valez, Lupe, 1929-1931; 35 items. (Box 22, Folder 48)
    6.5 x 8.5" and 5 x 8" black and white portraits. One set of black and white color values from Hessercolor photograph.
  - Wallace, Ramsey, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Watts, Peggy, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - White, Alice, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - Allison, May, ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    11 x 14" black and white print.
  - Amann, Betty "Bee", ca. 1925-1935; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    11 x 16" black and white print.
  - Ashcroft, Mary, ca. 1920-1938; 3 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    13 x 16" black and white portraits of woman in causal attire with head scarf.
  - Banky, Vilma, ca. 1920-1938; 3 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman wrapped in fabric. Includes one mounted print.
  - Bronson, Betty, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman in casual attire with a large hat. Includes one mounted print.
  - Byrne, Rosalind, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman semi-nude wrapped in lacy fabric, posed on a stool.
  - Caldwell, Betty, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman semi-nude wrapped in fabric.
  - Clark, Trilby, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman semi-nude wrapped in fabric with a head scarf.
  - Collyer, June, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    13 x 16" black and white portrait of woman in formal attire.
  - Cornwall, Anne, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 10)
    13 x 16" black and white portrait of woman in causal attire.
  - Daw, Marjorie, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman in casual attire.
  - Dawson, Dawn, ca. 1920-1938; 8 items. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman semi-nude and wrapped in fabric.
  - Dell, Claudia, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Dove, Billie, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 14)
    9.5 x 12.25" black and white mounted portrait of woman wrapped in fabric with pearls around her neck.
  - Gilmore, Glory, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Hughes, Gareth, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 16)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of man in costume with a crown of twigs.
  - Hyams, Leila, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 17)
    13 x 16" black and white mounted portrait of woman semi-nude wrapped in fabric.
  - Jewell, Betty, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 34, Folder 18)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman wrapped in fabric.
  - Johnston, Julanne, ca. 1920-1938; 4 items. (Box 34, Folder 19)
    11 x 14" black and white portraits of woman dressed in Middle Eastern costume attire. Includes one mounted print.
  - Knight, Lillian, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    11 x 14" black and white mounted portrait of Miss Los Angeles 1924 with trophies and ribbons.
  - Lee, Lila, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    11 x 14" black and white mounted portrait of woman wrapped in fabric.
  - Leet, Marjorie, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    11 x 14" black and white full body shot of woman semi-nude and wrapped in a see-through fabric.
  - Lockridge, Tay, ca. 1920-1938; 21 item. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    11 x 14" black and white portraits of woman in various poses wrapped in fabric.
  - Love, Bessie, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    11 x 14" black and white mounted portrait of woman in formal attire with pearls around her neck and holding a flower.
  - MacDonald, Katharine, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman wrapped in dark fabric.
  - McMahon, Cedrica, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman posing with flowers.
  - Moran, Lois, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    13 x 16" black and white mounted portrait of woman in casual attire with pearls around her neck.
  - Moris, Margaret, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman wrapped in fabric and with a head scarf.
  - O'Day, Molly, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    13 x 16" black and white portrait of woman wrapped in fabric around head and shoulders.
  - Patterson, Dial, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Ralston, Esther, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 12)
    9.5 x 12.25" black and white mounted portrait of woman wrapped in fabric.
  - Ricksen, Lucille, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Robbins, Betty, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Roche, John, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 15)
    13 x 16" black and white mounted portrait of man in casual attire.
  - Rolanda, Rose, ca. 1920-1938; 2 items. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    11 x 14" black and white full body shots of woman dressed in costumes.
  - Taylor, Ruth, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Winter, Dale, ca. 1920-1938; 5 items. (Box 35, Folder 18)
    11 x 14" black and white portraits of woman semi-nude wrapped in various fabrics and in a head scarf.
  - Worth, Barbara, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 19)
    11 x 14" black and white portrait of woman in shoulder-less dress.
  - Young, Loretta, ca. 1920-1938; 1 item. (Box 35, Folder 20)
    13 x 16" black and white mounted portrait of woman semi-nude with furry material.
- Prints, ca. 1920-1945; 6 boxes, 19 oversize boxes
  This series consists of black and white and Hessercolor prints of various sizes shot by Edwin Bower Hesser. Arranged in subseries A-D as follows:
  A. Large Hessercolor, ca.1932-1943
  B. Large black and white, ca. 1920-1945
  C. Small black and white, ca. 1925-1945
  D. Small Hessercolor, ca. 1932-1943.
  - A. Large Hessercolor, ca.1932-1943
    This subseries consists of 10 x 13" prints of Edwin Bower Hesser's color process known as Hessercolor. The photographs feature anonymous models in casual, semi-formal, and formal attire; nude, semi-nude, and erotic modeling women; women in costume and festive attire; women in bathing suits; women in winter clothes; men in military uniforms; couples; models with various props; theatrical and film scenes; aerial shots; and advertising shots. Files are arranged alphabetically according to subject and model.
    - Advertising photography (1 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      10 x 13" shots of advertisements for Pabst Beer and Green Spot Soda.
    - Advertising photography (2 of 2), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 41, Folder 2)
      10 x 13"shots of advertisements for Green Spot Soda.
    - Aerial shots (1 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      10 x 13" shots of landscapes taken from an airplane.
    - Aerial shots (2 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Aerial shots (3 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      10 x 13"shots of airplanes on ground and in flight. Includes shots of landscapes taken from an airplane.
    - Blonde Model A, ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      10 x 13" shots of an unidentified blonde model in hat, bathing suit, and with umbrella.
    - Blonde Model B, ca. 1932-1943; 8 items. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified blonde model in formal and casual attire. Includes semi-nude shots.
    - Blonde Model C, ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Blonde models (1 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 2)
      10 x 13" shots of various unidentified blonde models in formal and casual attire.
    - Blonde models (2 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Blonde models (3 of 3), ca. 1932-1943; 5 items. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Brunette Model A (1 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 7 items. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      10 x 13" shots of unidentified Brunette Model A posing in a gold top and a flower print top, posing with ship steering wheel.
    - Brunette Model A (2 of 10), ca. 1932-1943; 6 items. (Box 42, Folder 6)